Register of the Fritz Machlup Papers, 1911-1983
Hoover Institution Archives
- ACADEMIC CAREER, 1929-1983.
  - University of Buffalo, 1935-1947
    - Course material
      - "Socialism, Capitalism, and Economic Planning." Corespondence, examination questions, reading lists (Folder 3)
    - Student records (Folder 4)
    - Subject file. Mainly correspondence and notes
      - Economic Reading Club (Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 6)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1939
    - Correspondence (Folder 7)
    - Examination questions (Folder 8)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1949
    - Correspondence (Folder 9)
    - Mark sheets and comments (Folder 10)
  - University of Melbourne, 1970. Good-bye card from students (Folder 11)
  - University of Michigan, 1941. Correspondence and mark sheets (Folder 12)
  - University of Rochester, 1941-1942 (Fritz Machlup examiner). Correspondence, examination questions, mark sheets (Folder 13)
  - Volkshochschule Wien, 1929-1933. Correspondence and school annual report (Folder 14)
- OFFICE OF ALIEN PROPERTY CUSTODIAN, 1943-1946
  - General (Box 275, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Folder 2)
  - Historical monographs written in the Division of Research and Statistics
    - "A Brief Historical Summary of the Trading With the Enemy Act and Amendments Thereto, 1917-1940" (Folder 3)
    - "Developments in the Trade Mark Policy, July 1944 -July 1946" (Folder 4)
    - "History of the Administration of the Patents and Patent Contracts of General Aniline and Film Corporation by the Office of Alien Property Custodian" (Folder 5)
    - "History of the Establishment of the Philippine Office of the Office of Alien Property Custodian" (Folder 6)
    - "History of the Trade-Mark Policy of the Office of Alien Property Custodian" (Folder 7)
    - "History of Title III of the First War Powers Act Amending 5(b) of the Trading With the Enemy Act" (Folder 8)
    - "The Office of Alien Property Custodian and Relations With the Office of Censorship" (Folder 9)
    - "The Office of Alien Property Custodian and the Colombian Replacement Program" (Folder 10)
    - "The Office of Alien Property Custodian and World War I Property" (Folder 11)
    - "Treatment of Property of Interned Enemy Aliens" (Folder 12)
    - "The Vesting of the Stock, Patent, and Patent Contract Rights of General Aniline and Film Corporation by the Office of Alien Property Custodian" (Folder 13)
  - Memoranda. Includes correspondence
    - General (Box 276, Folder 1)
    - Cartel Committee (Folder 2)
    - Machlup, Fritz
      - 1943 (Folder 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 4)
      - 1945 (Box 277, Folder 1)
      - 1946 (Folder 2)
    - Re captive patents (Folder 3-4)
    - Re Fritz Machlup's resignation, 1946 (Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 6)
  - Notes (Folder 7)
  - Reports by Fritz Machlup
    - General
      - Progress reports, 1943-1946 (Box 278, Folder 1-2)
      - Final report, 1946 (Folder 3)
    - "Report on the Expansion Program of General Aniline and Film Corporation," 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Research material (Folder 5-10)
  - Writings by Fritz Machlup
    - "Arguments Pro and Con Non-Exclusive Licensing" (Folder 11)
    - "Disposition after the War of the Property Acquired by the APC" (Folder 12)
    - "Exploratory Notes on the Concept of 'Reasonable Royalties'" (Folder 13)
    - "Legislation Relating to Patents" (Folder 14)
    - "A Neglected Phase of International Economies: The Role of Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights in International Economic Relations" (Folder 15)
    - "The Secret Formula: The Law versus Common Sense" (Folder 16)
- MONT PELERIN SOCIETY, 1946-1983
  - General (Box 279, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence. Includes memoranda and minutes of meetings
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Baudin, Louis, 1960 (Folder 3)
    - Bauer, P. T., 1957 (Folder 4)
    - Bohm, Franz, 1960-1962 (Folder 5)
    - Brandt, Karl, 1962 (Folder 6)
    - Cornuelle, Richard C., 1963 (Folder 7)
    - Crane, Jasper E., 1957-1965 (Folder 8)
    - Davenport, John, 1959 (Folder 9)
    - Director, Aaron, 1960 (Folder 10)
    - Erhard, Ludwig, 1961 (Folder 11)
    - Frickhoffer, Wolfgang, 1961 (Folder 12)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1961 (Folder 13)
    - Gudin, Eugenio, 1959-1967 (Folder 14)
    - Hamilius, Jean-Pierre, 1975-1978 (Folder 15)
    - Harris, Ralph, 1967-1979 (Folder 16)
    - Hayek, Friedrich A. von, 1946-1962 (Folder 17)
    - Hazlitt, Henry, 1961 (Folder 18)
    - Hoff, Trygve J. B., 1961 (Folder 19)
    - Hunold, Albert, 1947-1961 (Folder 20)
    - Ilau, Hans, 1958-1961 (Box 280, Folder 1)
    - Jewkes, John, 1959-1962 (Folder 2)
    - Kemp, Arthur, 1961-1976 (Folder 3)
    - Leduc, Gaston, 1971-1972 (Folder 4)
    - Leoni, Bruno, 1960-1968 (Folder 5)
    - Notten, Michael van, 1976 (Folder 6)
    - Offelen, Jacques Van, 1962 (Folder 7)
    - Philbrook, Clarence E., 1955-1964 (Folder 8)
    - Read, Leonard, 1960-1964 (Folder 9)
    - Riboud, Jacques, 1975 (Folder 10)
    - Ropke, Wilhelm, 1955-1961 (Folder 11)
    - Schoeck, Helmut, 1960 (Folder 12)
    - Shaw, H. Harland, 1962 (Folder 13)
    - Shenfield, Arthur A., 1960-1976 (Folder 14)
    - Stigler, George J., 1960 (Folder 15)
    - Tanaka, Seigen, 1969 (Folder 16)
    - Thurn, Max, 1961-1979 (Folder 17)
    - Van Sickle, John V., 1961 (Folder 18)
    - Villey, Daniel, 1962 (Folder 19)
  - Proceedings of general and regional meetings
    - 1947-1965 (Folder 20-34)
    - 1966-1983 (Box 281, Folder 1-19)
  - Publications
    - Quarterly journals, 1959-1962 (Folder 20)
    - Newsletters, 1972-1981 (Folder 21)
- GROUP OF THIRTY (CONSULTATIVE GROUP ON INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC AND MONETARY AFFAIRS), 1963-1982
  - General
    - General (Box 282, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - Ford Foundation, 1963-1974. Includes financial records and correspondence with Princeton University and William J. Fellner (Folder 2)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1963-1966 (Folder 3)
      - Other foundations, 1963 (Folder 4)
    - Financial records (Folder 5)
  - Bellagio Group (also called Machlup Group or Group of 32 Non-Governmental Economists), 1963-1964
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Proceedings of meetings
      - 1963 December (Princeton, New Jersey) (Folder 7)
      - 1964
        - January (Bellagio, Italy) (Folder 8)
        - March (Princeton) (Folder 9)
        - May (Bellagio) (Folder 10)
  - Joint Conference of Officials and Academics on International Monetary Reform, 1964-1978
    - Correspondence
      - Unidentified (Folder 11)
      - Ansiaux, Hubert, 1969 (Folder 12)
      - Barbosa, Manuel Pinto, 1972 (Folder 13)
      - Baroody, William J., 1971 (Folder 14)
      - Bennett, Jack F., 1974 (Folder 15)
      - Boyer de la Giroday, Frederic, 1969-1974 (Folder 16)
      - Carli, Guido, 1968-1972 (Folder 17)
      - Clappier, B., 1970-1975 (Folder 18)
      - Cooper, Richard N., 1966 (Folder 19)
      - Daane, J. Dewey, 1966-1972 (Folder 20)
      - Deguen, Daniel, 1973 (Folder 21)
      - Deif, Nazih Ahmed, 1972 (Folder 22)
      - De Marchi, Neil, 1974 (Folder 23)
      - Deming, Frederick L., 1966 (Folder 24)
      - De Vries, Thomas, 1966 (Folder 25)
      - Dow, Christopher, 1966-1973 (Folder 26)
      - Drees, W., Jr., 1970 (Folder 27)
      - Emminger, Otmar, 1971 (Folder 28)
      - Figgures, Frank E., 1970-1971 (Folder 29)
      - Fleming, J. Marcus, 1966-1972 (Folder 30)
      - Gilbert, Milton, 1966-1973 (Folder 31)
      - Giscard d'Estaing, Valery, 1971 (Folder 32)
      - Gocht, R., 1965-1966 (Folder 33)
      - Haberler, Gottfried, 1971 (Folder 34)
      - Hiss, Dieter, 1972-1974 (Folder 35)
      - Hood, William C., 1973 (Folder 36)
      - Inamura, Koichi, 1972-1975 (Folder 37)
      - Jayawardena, Lal, 1972-1973 (Folder 38)
      - Kafka, Alexandre, 1971-1976 (Folder 39)
      - Kashiwagi, Yusuke, 1968-1972 (Folder 40)
      - Kennedy, David M., 1969 (Folder 41)
      - Kessler, G. A., 1970-1972 (Folder 42)
      - Larre, Rene (and Jacques de Larosiere) (Box 283, Folder 1)
      - Lawson, R. W., 1966 (Folder 2)
      - Lutz, Friedrich A., 1972 (Folder 3)
      - Martin, William McC., Jr., 1969 (Folder 4)
      - McMahon, Christopher W., 1968-1975 (Folder 5)
      - Meade, James E., 1972 (Folder 6)
      - Mertens de Wilmars, Jacques, 1964-1972 (Folder 7)
      - Mitchell, Derek J., 1972-1974 (Folder 8)
      - Morse, Jeremy, 1972-1974 (Folder 9)
      - Navarro Rubio, Mariano, 1970 (Folder 10)
      - Neale, Alan D., 1971-1972 (Folder 11)
      - Neild, Robert, 1966 (Folder 12)
      - O'Brien, Sir Leslie, 1972 (Folder 13)
      - Oort, Conrad J., 1972-1975 (Folder 14)
      - Ortoli, Francois-Xavier, 1969 (Folder 15)
      - Ossola, Rinaldo, 1966 (Folder 16)
      - Palamenghi-Crispi, Francesco, 1971-1973 (Folder 17)
      - Parsons, Sir Maurice, 1966-1968 (Folder 18)
      - Patel, I. G., 1971 (Folder 19)
      - Perez-Guerrero, Manuel, 1971 (Folder 20)
      - Perouse, Maurice, 1966 (Folder 21)
      - Pierre-Brossolette, Claude, 1966-1973 (Folder 22)
      - Pohl, Karl Otto, 1974-1975 (Folder 23)
      - Polak, Jacques J., 1971-1972 (Folder 24)
      - Rasminsky, Louis, 1969 (Folder 25)
      - Rawlinson, Anthony K., 1970-1971 (Folder 26)
      - Ray, G. F., 1971 (Folder 27)
      - Rickett, Sir Dennis, 1969-1973 (Folder 28)
      - Roosa, Robert V., 1972-1973 (Folder 29)
      - Salin, Pascal, 1972 (Folder 30)
      - Schmitz, Wolfgang, 1971 (Folder 31)
      - Scitovsky, Tibor, 1972 (Folder 32)
      - Segre, Claudio, 1968-1970 (Folder 33)
      - Sohmen, Egon, 1972-1973 (Folder 34)
      - Solomon, Robert, 1969-1974 (Folder 35)
      - Strycker, Cecil de, 1966-1971 (Folder 36)
      - Uri, Pierre, 1966 (Folder 37)
      - Vlerick, A., 1972 (Folder 38)
      - Volcker, Paul A., 1969-1973 (Folder 39)
      - Wallich, Henry C., 1970-1971 (Folder 40)
      - Willis, George H., 1972 (Folder 41)
      - Zijlstra, J., 1969-1972 (Folder 42)
    - List of deputies of the Group of Ten and of the Ossola Committee (Folder 43)
    - Proceedings of meetings
      - Undated (Folder 44)
      - 1964 December (Bellagio) (Folder 45)
      - 1966 January (Zurich, Switzerland) (Folder 46)
      - 1967
        - March and June (Bellagio) (Folder 47-48)
        - September (Rio de Janeiro, Brazil) (Folder 49)
      - 1968
        - May (Bologna, Italy) (Folder 50)
        - September (Princeton) (Folder 51)
      - 1969
        - March (Lugano, Switzerland) (Folder 52)
        - September (Princeton) (Folder 53)
      - 1970 March (Torremolinos, Spain) (Folder 54)
      - 1971
        - January (Taormina, Italy) (Folder 55)
        - September (Washington, D.C.) (Folder 56)
      - 1972 March (Cascais, Portugal) (Folder 57)
      - 1973
        - January (Vienna, Austria) (Box 284, Folder 1)
        - October (Princeton) (Folder 2)
      - 1974 February (Versailles, France) (Folder 3)
      - 1975 January-February (Basle, Switzerland) (Folder 4)
      - 1977 March (Basle) (Folder 5)
  - Group of Thirty, 1978-1982
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. Includes memoranda and reports (Folder 5)
      - 1978. Includes correspondence with the Rockefeller Foundation (Folder 7)
      - 1979-1982 (Folder 8)
    - Membership lists (Box 285, Folder 1)
    - Press release, 1981 April 14 (Folder 2)
    - Proceedings of meetings
      - 1979
        - February (Hamilton, Bermuda) (Folder 3)
        - October (Opatija, Yugoslavia) (Folder 4)
      - 1980 October (Charlottesville, Virginia) (Folder 5)
      - 1982 September (Toronto, Canada) (Folder 6)
    - Publications (Folder 7)
    - Speeches and writings by members (Folder 8)
- BURGENSTOCK GROUP, 1968-1971
  - General (Box 285, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1968 (Folder 10)
      - 1969 (Folder 11)
    - Ford Foundation. (Folder 12)
      See also GROUP OF THIRTY, Correspondence, Ford Foundation
  - Proceedings of meetings
    - Undated (Williamsburg, Virginia) (Folder 13)
    - 1969
      - January (Oyster Bay, New York) (Folder 14)
      - June (Burgenstock, Switzerland) (Folder 15)
      - October (Washington, D.C.) (Folder 16)
    - 1970 January (Arden House, New York) (Folder 17)
    - 1971 February (Tarrytown House, New York) (Folder 18)
- AMERICAN ASSOCIATION OF UNIVERSITY PROFESSORS, 1952-1982
  - General (Box 286, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General, including with Peggy Heim (staff associate) (Folder 2-3)
    - With university presidents
      - 1957-1962 (Folder 4)
      - 1963-1971 (Folder 5)
  - Letters of appreciation (Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 7)
  - Resolution honoring Fritz Machlup (Folder 8)
  - Subject file. Correspondence, lists, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, statements, clippings
    - Academic freedom and tenure
      - General (Box 287, Folder 1-2)
      - Johns Hopkins University (Folder 3)
      - Princeton University (Folder 4)
    - Attacks on the AAUP for being soft on communism (Folder 5)
    - Code of ethics (Folder 6)
    - Collective bargaining (Folder 7)
    - Meiklejohn Award (Folder 8)
    - Princeton University Chapter (Folder 9)
    - Salaries
      - General
        - General (Box 288, Folder 1)
        - Committee Z (Folder 2-3)
        - Sub-Committee Z
          - 1957-1960 (Folder 4)
          - 1961 (Folder 5)
          - 1962-1964 (Folder 6)
      - Johns Hopkins University (Folder 7)
- AMERICAN ECONOMIC ASSOCIATION, 1935-1982
  - General (Box 289, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1935-1943 (Folder 2)
    - 1944-1947 (Folder 3)
    - 1948-1966 (Folder 4)
    - 1967-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Subject file. Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, statements, printed matter
    - Committees
      - Academic Freedom and Civil Liberties (Box 290, Folder 1)
      - Classification (Folder 2)
      - Foreign Honorary Members (Folder 3)
      - Honors and Awards
        - 1950-1959 (Folder 4)
        - 1960-1965 (Folder 5)
      - Nominating Committee (Folder 6)
    - Projects
      - Foreign Students Screening (Box 291, Folder 1)
      - Index of Economic Journals (Folder 2)
      - US/USSR Symposium. Includes correspondence with the Ford Foundation
        - 1972-1974 (Folder 3)
        - 1975-1976 (Folder 4)
- INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC ASSOCIATION, 1951-1983
  - General (Box 291, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1968-1972 (Folder 6)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 292, Folder 1)
      - 1975-1982 (Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation. Includes financial records
      - 1971 (Folder 3)
      - 1972 (Folder 4)
      - 1973 (Folder 5)
      - 1974-1976 (Folder 6)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 293, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of meetings of the Executive Committee
    - 1971-1973 (Folder 2)
    - 1974 (Folder 3)
    - 1975-1980 (Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 5)
  - Newsletters (Folder 6)
  - Proceedings of conferences, congresses, and workshops
    - 1951 September (Talloires, France) (Box 294, Folder 1)
    - 1962 August-September (Vienna, Austria) (Folder 2)
    - 1963 August-September (Menthon St. Bernard, France) (Folder 3)
    - 1968 September (Montreal, Canada) (Folder 4)
    - 1969 August-September (Algarve, Portugal) (Folder 5)
    - 1970 August (Bled, Yugoslavia) (Folder 6)
    - 1971
      - July-August (Bergen, Norway) (Folder 7)
      - August-September (St. Anton-am-Arlberg, Austria) (Folder 8)
      - December (Mexico City, Mexico) (Folder 9)
    - 1972
      - June (Lyngby, Denmark) (Folder 10)
      - August-September (Bad Godesberg, Germany) (Folder 11)
      - December (Moscow, Soviet Union) (Folder 12)
    - 1973
      - January (Dacca, Bangladesh) (Folder 13)
      - April (Tokyo, Japan) (Folder 14)
      - June-July (Rheda, Germany) (Box 295, Folder 1)
      - September (Valescure, France) (Folder 2)
    - 1974
      - April (Turin, Italy) (Folder 3)
      - August (Budapest, Hungary) (Folder 4-7)
      - August (Budapest) (Box 296, Folder 1-4)
      - August (Budapest) (Box 297, Folder 1-5)
      - September (Istambul, Turkey) (Folder 6)
    - 1975
      - April (S'Agaro, Spain) (Folder 7)
      - July (Kiel, Germany) (Folder 8)
    - 1976
      - June-July (Dresden, East Germany) (Folder 9)
      - September
        - (Urbino, Italy) (Folder 10)
        - (Teheran, Iran) (Folder 11)
    - 1977
      - Spring
        - (Mexico City) (Box 298, Folder 1)
        - (Netherlands) - postponed (Folder 2)
      - August-September (Tokyo) (Folder 3)
    - 1978
      - (Netherlands?) - planned (Folder 4)
      - June (Poland) (Folder 5)
    - 1980 August (Mexico City) (Folder 6)
    - 1983
      - July (Addis Ababa, Ethiopia) (Folder 7)
      - September (Madrid, Spain) (Folder 8)
  - Report 1971-1974 (Folder 9)
  - Subject file. Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes
    - Committee on Labor Productivity (John T. Dunlop). Relates mainly to the East-West conferences (Folder 10)
    - Conferences and congresses, including topics for (Folder 11-12)
    - Donors (Folder 13)
    - Presidents of the IEA (Folder 14)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1982.
  Conference papers, correspondence, memoranda, notes, press releases, speeches, statements, reports, studies, newsletters, and printed matter
  - Austria (Box 299, Folder 1)
  - Bohm-Bawerk, Eugen von (Folder 2)
  - Bonaparte, Napoleon (Folder 3)
  - Council of Engineering and Scientific Society Executives (Folder 4)
  - Economics
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Austrian (Folder 6)
    - International (Folder 7)
  - Education (Folder 8-10)
  - Ehrlich, Otto H. (Folder 11)
  - European Communities (Folder 12)
  - Gaitskell, Hugh (Box 300, Folder 1)
  - Germany (Folder 2)
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander (Folder 3)
  - Giersch, Herbert (Folder 4)
  - Godel, Kurt (Folder 5)
  - Gold (Folder 6)
  - Great Britain (Folder 7)
  - Haberler, Gottfried (Folder 8)
  - Hahn, L. Albert (Folder 9)
  - Harvard University (Folder 10)
  - Hayek, Friedrich A. von
    - General (Folder 11)
    - Luncheon for, 1945 April 13 (Folder 12)
  - Hollander, David H. (Folder 13)
  - Hurt, Robert M. (Folder 14)
  - Inflation (Folder 15)
  - International finance (Folder 16)
  - International finance (Box 301, Folder 1-4)
  - International trade (Folder 5-7)
  - Japan (Box 302, Folder 1)
  - Joint Council on Economic Education (Folder 2)
  - Kamitz, Reinhard (Folder 3)
  - Keynes, John Maynard (Folder 4)
  - Knight, Frank H. (Folder 5)
  - Knowledge industry (Folder 6-9)
  - Knowledge industry (Box 303, Folder 1)
  - Lattimore, Owen.
    See ACADEMIC CAREER, Johns Hopkins University, Correspondence, General (1955)
  - Lattimore Defense Fund (Folder 2)
  - Menger, Carl (Folder 3)
  - Methodology (Folder 4-6)
  - Methodology (Box 304, Folder 1-4)
  - Methodology (Box 305, Folder 1)
  - Minimum wage (Folder 2-3)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
  - Mises, Ludwig von (Box 306, Folder 1)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar (Folder 2)
  - Munakata, Hisonari (Folder 3)
  - National Academy of Education.
    See SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, Knowledge..., Research material, Vol. V (Box 155)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (Folder 4)
  - National Resources Planning Board (Folder 5)
  - National Science Foundation (Folder 6)
  - National Taxpayers Union (Folder 7)
  - New Deal (Folder 8)
  - Nobel Prize in economics (Folder 9)
  - Ohlin, Bertil (Folder 10)
  - Osterreichisches Institut fur Wirtschaftsforschung (Folder 11)
  - Patents
    - General (Folder 12-17)
    - General (Box 307, Folder 1-5)
    - General (Box 308, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - Bureaux Internationaux Reunis pour la Protection de la Propriete Industrielle Litteraire et Artistique, 1961-1962 (Folder 2)
      - E.I. du Pont de Nemours and Company, 1961-1963 (Folder 3)
      - General Electric Company, 1958-1961 (Folder 4)
      - Government Patents Board, 1950 (Folder 5)
      - Kaplan, Benjamin, 1964 (Folder 6)
      - Library of Congress, 1961 (Folder 7)
      - Lippert, Arnold L., 1961 (Folder 8)
      - McGaw, Foster G., 1961 (Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 10)
      - National Association of Manufacturers, 1961 (Folder 11)
      - Polaroid Corporation, 1961-1962 (Folder 12)
      - Pretnar, Sto jan, 1964-1972 (Folder 13)
      - Research Corporation, 1960-1962 (Folder 14)
      - Shipman, John R., 1967 (Folder 15)
      - Steele, Henry, 1964 (Folder 16)
      - United States. Department of Commerce, 1961 (Folder 17)
      - Ybbstaler Pappenfabriken Adolf Leitner und Bruder (Josef Leitner), 1960-1962 (Folder 18)
  - Performance, Economic and social (Box 309, Folder 1)
  - Petrochemicals (Folder 2)
  - Poverty (Folder 3)
  - Public debt (Folder 4)
  - Putz, Theodor (Folder 5)
  - Research and development (Folder 6-8)
  - Samuelson, Paul (Folder 9)
  - Schpeter, Henrich Natan (Folder 10)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph H. (Folder 11)
  - Schutz, Alfred (Folder 12)
  - Schweizerisches Institut fur Auslandforschung (Folder 13)
  - Science (Folder 14)
  - Sklar Commission to Revise the Public Service Commission Law of Maryland (Box 310, Folder 1)
  - Spann, Othmar (Folder 2)
  - Statistical sampling (Folder 3)
  - Strong, Benjamin (Folder 4)
  - Taussig, Frank W. (Folder 5)
  - Trade unions (Folder 6)
  - United States (Folder 7)
  - US/USSR Joint Commission on Scientific and Technical Cooperation (Folder 8-12)
  - Vecchio, Gustavo del (Box 311, Folder 1)
  - Vienna Circle (Folder 2)
  - Viner, Jacob (Folder 3)
  - Welter, Erich (Folder 4)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A. (Folder 5)
- WRITINGS BY OTHERS, 1927-1981
  - Beth, Evert Willem (Box 311, Folder 6)
  - Haberler, Gottfried (Folder 7-9)
  - Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Box 312, Folder 1-3)
  - Johnson, Harry G. (Box 313, Folder 1)
  - Kaufmann, Felix (Folder 2)
  - Meade, James E. (Folder 3)
  - Menger, Karl (Folder 4)
  - Mises, Ludwig von (Folder 5)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar (Folder 6)
- INDEX CARD FILE, n.d.
  - Address file (Box 314)
  - Book order file (Box 314-315)
  - Reading and research notes, including for specific speeches and writings, and for class instruction (Box 316-317)
    - Miscellaneous
    - International trade (Box 318)
    - Macroeconomics
    - Methodology (Box 319)
    - Money and banking
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1922-1982
  - Bound volumes of speeches and writings. Includes some clippings of Fritz Machlup and family
    - A (1922-1963) (Box 320)
    - B (1932-1934)
    - C (1932-1982) (Box 321)
    - D (1960-1981)
    - E (1923-1952) (Box 322)
    - 2 ("English Essays and Articles, 1932-1940")
    - 3 ("Articles, 1941-1950")
    - 4 ("Reviews, Discussions, and Reports, 1930-1960") (Box 323)
    - 5 ("Articles and Essays, 1951-1960")
    - 6 ("Articles and Essays, 1960-1966")
    - 7 ("Articles and Essays in English, 1967-1971") (Box 324)
    - 8 ("Articles and Essays in English, 1972-1976") (Box 325)
    - 9 ("Articles and Essays in Foreign Languages, 1966-1975") (Box 326)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings relating to Fritz Machlup and family (Box 327)
    - 1935-1959 (3 volumes)
    - 1960-1978 (2 volumes) (Box 328)
- MEMORABILIA, 1923-1982.
  - Awards, certificates, citations, commemorative albums, honorary degrees, medals, and plaques (Box Boxes 329-330)
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1973-1981
  - Phonotapes (Tape-cabint Tape cabinet)
    - Dictation of correspondence, n.d. (in German) (Tape-cabint 1)
    - "Foreign Debts, Reparations, and the Transfer Problem," n.d. Dictation of the revised version of an article published in German in 1928 and translated by Mr. Lang (Tape-cabint 2-3)
    - "If Matter Could Talk," 1973. Speech, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan (Tape-cabint 4)
  - Phonotape cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
    - "Friedrich A. von Hayek and His Early Work in Technical Economics," 1975 August 25. Speech, Mont Pelerin Society, Hillsdale, Michigan. Includes comments by Milton Friedman, Fred Glahe, Arthur Kemp, G. P. O'Driscoll, Jr. (Cassette-cabinet 5-6)
    - Participation, "Looking Toward the 21st Century," Tokyo Colloquium, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan, 1976 September 28 (Cassette-cabinet 7)
    - "The World Monetary Order," 1981 November 18. Speech, State Bank of Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan (Cassette-cabinet 8)